(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
お誕生日生配信 / 3D配信 / 猫又おかゆ / おかゆの生誕祭2021
Birthday Live Stream / 3D Stream / Nekomata Okayu / Okayu's Birthday Festival 2021
ピンポンパンポーン
[Chime sound]
どうやら運営さんが、半泣きになりながらね、
It seems the staff members, while half-crying,
機材を頑張って弄ってくれたおかげで
worked hard to fix the equipment, and thanks to that,
直りましたー！
it's fixed now!
待ってくださった皆さんありがとうございます。
Thank you all for waiting.
え、先程見れなかったために、えーと見れなかった方のたために、さっきと同じね
For those who couldn't see it earlier, I will play the same...
映像を流します。
...video as before.
これから、ちゃんと、お誕生日3D配信開始いたしますので、しっかりみんな
I will now properly start the Birthday 3D stream, so everyone...
目に焼き付けてくれよなー！
...make sure to burn it into your eyes!
では、ゴー！
Now, let's go!
お！お！おおー！
Oh! Oh! Ooh!
始まってるじゃないか。
It's started, hasn't it?
はーい、皆さん、こんばんはー！
Hi everyone, good evening!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆでーす。
I'm Nekomata Okayu of Hololive Gamers.
今日は僕のお誕生日会に遊びに来てくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday party today!
今日はですね、僕のホロライブに入ってから2回目の誕生日ということで、
Today is my second birthday since joining Hololive,
なんかこう去年とは違うことがしたいなって思ったので、
so I thought I wanted to do something different from last year.
今回はね、今までやったことがない歌ライブに挑戦してみようかなと思います！
This time, I'm going to challenge myself with a singing live, which I've never done before!
しかもね、僕一人で配信する時にこのアイドル衣装を使うのは初めてなんじゃないかな。
Also, I think this might be the first time I've used this idol costume for a solo stream.
いや、すごい僕もね、楽しみにしてたし、
Yeah, I've been really looking forward to it,
この日のためにたくさん練習してきたこととか、準備してきたこととかたくさんあるので、
and there are many things I've practiced and prepared for this day,
みんなに楽しんでいってもらえればなと思います。
so I hope everyone can enjoy it.
あとこの、こっちか、このリボンがね、よく見ると
And this... this side? If you look closely at this ribbon,
なんかおにぎりの体みたいになってるのがちょっとじわるなって、
it looks a bit like the shape of an onigiri, which is kind of amusing.
ちょっと着替えて身に着けてから思いました。
I thought that after I changed and put it on.
えー、あとはね、今日のハッシュタグのお知らせです。
And now, an announcement about today's hashtag.
ハッシュタグ「おかゆの生誕祭2021」で呟いてくれると、
If you tweet with the hashtag #OkayuNoSeitansai2021,
僕が配信終わった後にね、Twitterでペッペッペッって見てる時に
it'll be easier for me to find when I'm browsing Twitter after the stream.
探しやすいので、ぜひハッシュタグ「おかゆの生誕祭2021」で呟いてください。
So please tweet with the hashtag #OkayuNoSeitansai2021.
「の」だからね、大事なのは「の」だからね！
It's 'no' (の), okay? The important part is 'no'!
「の」がないと違うタグになっちゃうからね。
If there's no 'no', it'll be a different tag.
みんななら「の」ちゃんと入れられるって信じてるからね。
I believe you all can put the 'no' in properly.
はい、ということで、あ、運営さんからね、
Alright, then... oh, the staff mentioned
なんかケーキが届いてるとかなんか言ってたんだけど、
that a cake had arrived or something,
ケーキなんてないよね。
but there's no cake, is there?
ん？あ！
Huh? Ah!
出てきたー！ケーキだー！
It appeared! It's a cake!
え、これ全部、うわ！フライング、フライングだよフライング！
Wait, all of this... Whoa! It's flying! It's flying!
フライング...
Premature...
フライングでケーキ取っちゃったんですけど
I ended up grabbing the cake a bit prematurely.
えー、これがね、あのー僕に用意してくれたケーキらしくて、
Um, this is apparently the cake they prepared for me,
本来ならね、こうやってブスって刺すとこから始めたかったんですけど
and normally, I would have started by stabbing it like this, but...
僕のこの手際の悪さで、手癖の悪さでケーキをもうキャッチしてしまいました。
Due to my clumsiness and my bad habits, I ended up catching the cake.
でもこのケーキ早速ね、頂いちゃおうかなと思います。やっぱ美味しそうなんでね。
But I think I'll go ahead and dig into this cake. It looks so delicious.
じゃあ、いただきます。
Well then, let's eat.
ムニャムニャ...
Munch munch...
美味しい！
Delicious!
美味しいー！
It's delicious!
え、みんなも食べたいの？
Oh, do you guys want to eat some too?
どうしようかな...
What should I do...?
食べたいですかー？
Do you want to eat?
お？聞こえない、よく聞こえない。
Oh? I can't hear you, I can't hear you very well.
え？
Eh?
もっともっともっと。
More, more, more!
食べたいですかー？
Do you want to eat?!
しょうがないな。
Alright then.
じゃあ、特別にね。
Then, as a special treat.
おにぎり、カモン！
Onigiri, come on!
キター！
Here it is!
これがね、みんなに食べさせようと思ってたケーキです。
This is the cake I was planning to feed all of you.
どらー！
There!
食えー！
Eat up!
はい、あーん。
Now, say "ahh".
ムニャムニャ...
Munch munch...
あー、美味しいね！美味しかった？
Ah, it's delicious! Was it good?
よかった。
I'm glad.
この底の、底についてる生クリームと海苔のハーモニーが、
The harmony of the whipped cream on the bottom and the seaweed...
絶妙なんじゃないですか？絶妙ですよね。
Isn't it exquisite? It's exquisite, isn't it?
よし、みんながおにぎりケーキを食べたということで、
Alright, now that everyone has eaten the onigiri cake,
僕はそろそろ歌のライブの準備に向かいたいと思います！
I'm going to go get ready for the song performance!
じゃあみんな、あとに続けー！
Okay everyone, follow me!
はっ！
Ha!
彗星ハネムーン / 作詞・作曲：ナユタン星人
Comet Honeymoon / Lyrics & Composition: Nayutalien
Mmm, mmm, mmm...
キラキラ光る流星群
Twinkling, shining meteor shower
わたし想うわウォーアイニー
I'm thinking, "Wo ai ni"
星のまにまに逃避行
A flight to escape among the stars
嗚呼、そんなストーリーも悪くないのさ
Ah, that kind of story isn't so bad either
ネオンの街からプレビュー
Preview from the neon city
月世界までウォンビーロン
All the way to the moon, won't be long
あの星の名も忘れたの
I even forgot the name of that star
満ち月の飛行
A flight across the full moon
彗星ハネムーン　あなたとランデヴ
Comet honeymoon, a rendezvous with you
恋しているのさふたり
The two of us are in love
愛してモナムール　いっそ、ふたりきり
Love me, mon amour. Let's just be the two of us.
どっか遠くへいこうか
Shall we go somewhere far away?
曖昧なエアライン　言葉はいらない
Vague airline, no words are needed
やっと出逢えたあなたと
With you, whom I've finally met
星巡り　繰り返し
Traveling around the stars, again and again
目指すは宇宙の終着点さ
Aiming for the end of the universe
アハハーン　アハハーン　アハハン
Ah-ha-haaan, ah-ha-haaan, ah-ha-han
アハハーン　アハハーン　うおお
Ah-ha-haaan, ah-ha-haaan, uooo
はっ！
Ha!
小天体のライナー　その数回転のあいだ
Liner of a small celestial body, during its few rotations
運命星も越えた　愛の瞬きがプレイバック
Crossing the stars of fate, the blink of love plays back
環状線繋いだ　あなたは終点ライダー
Connecting the loop line, you're the terminal rider
ロマンス飛行を今
A romance flight, right now
動かない信号の赤色
The red of a non-moving traffic light
月世界までウォーアイニー
All the way to the moon, wo ai ni
モスクワの海が旅の終わり
The Sea of Moscow is the end of the journey
そこでお別れさ
That's where we'll say goodbye
彗星ハネムーン　あなたとランデヴ
Comet honeymoon, a rendezvous with you
恋しているのさふたり
The two of us are in love
愛してモナムール　由縁なんてなくても
Love me, mon amour, even if there's no reason
いいよ遠くへいこうか
It's okay, let's go somewhere far away
彗星ハネムーン　果てまでランデヴ
Comet honeymoon, a rendezvous to the very end
そうさ今だけはふたり
That's right, for now, it's just the two of us
ねえ聞いてモナムール　片道切符でもいいですよ？
Hey, listen, mon amour. A one-way ticket is fine too, you know?
夜が明けたら何処へいこうか？
Where shall we go when the dawn breaks?
永久に出逢えぬあなたと
With you, whom I'll never meet for eternity
星巡り　繰り返し
Traveling around the stars, again and again
目指すは夢の出発点さ
Aiming for the starting point of a dream
目指すは夢の終着点さ
Our destination is the end point of dreams.
アハハーン アハハーン あははん
Aha-haan Aha-haan Ahahan
アハハーン アハハーン うおお
Aha-haan Aha-haan Uoo!
アハハーン アハハーン
Aha-haan Aha-haan
アハハーン わー
Aha-haan Waa!
はぁー... 聞こえてますか？皆さん。
Haa... Can you hear me, everyone?
疲れだー
I'm exhausted!
はぁ、体力がないから
Haa, I have no stamina, so...
歌いながら動くとやばいマジで。はぁー...
...moving while singing is really tough. Seriously. Haa...
なんかね、さっきTwitterでさ、僕の枠がうまく行かなかったでしょ？
You know, earlier on Twitter, my stream link wasn't working, right?
でそん時にさ、ホロライブのみんながさ、
And at that time, everyone in Hololive...
なんかおかゆの新しい枠はこっちだよーみたいな風にさ、
...was posting things like, "Okayu's new stream link is here!"
なんか連絡してくれてるの見て、もうさ、ちょっと泣きそうになっちゃった。
Seeing them all spread the word... Man, I almost started crying.
なんかもうさ、ちょっと不安になっちゃってさ。
I was getting a bit anxious...
なんか今日放送できないのかな？って思ったんだけどさ。
...thinking maybe I wouldn't be able to stream today.
それでもみんな信じて、なんか枠の誘導してくれてるの見てさ、
But seeing everyone believe in me and guide people to the new link...
もうなんか、もう感無量だよ僕。
...I'm just overwhelmed with emotion.
これから始まったばっかりなのに。
And we've only just started.
はぁ、まぁいいや。えっと、あの、どうでした？水星ハネムーンは。
Haa, well, anyway. Um, so, how was 'Suisei Honeymoon'?
ちょっとくるくるこうやってね、回ってみたりとかしましたけど。
I tried spinning around a bit like this.
良かったかな？可愛かったかな？
Was it good? Was I cute?
ちょっとみんなにね、可愛いって思ってもらえるように動こうと思ってたから、そう思ってもらえたならね、良かった。良かったです。
I wanted to move in a way that would make everyone think I'm cute, so if you thought so, then I'm glad. I'm really glad.
はぁー... やばい。なんかこのまま喋り続けてるとさ、なんか泣いちゃいそうだからもう次に行こうと思います。
Haa... Oh man. If I keep talking like this, I feel like I'm going to cry, so let's move on to the next one.
運営さんいいですか？次、音楽のミュージックの準備はOKですか？
Staff, is it okay? Is the music ready for the next one?
OKとのことなので、次行きたいと思います。次の曲はこちら！
They said it's OK, so I'll head to the next one. The next song is this!
Please don't say "You are lazy" だって本当は crazy
Please don't say "You are lazy" Because I'm actually crazy
白鳥たちはそう 見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Swans, you see, kick their legs where no one can see
本能に従順 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
Obedient and faithful to instinct, well aware of being toyed with
前途洋々だし... だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright... so I take a break every now and then
Don't say "lazy" 作詞:大森祥子 / 作曲:前澤寛之
Don't say "lazy" / Lyrics: Shoko Omori / Composition: Hiroyuki Maezawa
この目しっかり見定めて 行き先地図上マークして
Look closely with these eyes and mark the destination on the map
近道あればそれが王道 はしょれる翼もあれば上等
If there's a shortcut, that's the royal road; it's great if there are wings to skip ahead
ヤバ爪割れた グルーで補修した
Oh no, my nail broke; I fixed it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感
Just that gives me a sense of accomplishment
大事なのは自分 かわいがること
The important thing is to love yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ他人(ひと)も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others
Please don't say "You are lazy" だって本当は crazy
Please don't say "You are lazy" Because I'm actually crazy
能ある鷹はそう 見えないとこにピック隠すんです
A talented hawk, you see, hides its pick where it can't be seen
想像に一生懸命 現実は絶体絶命
Working hard on imagination, while reality is a desperate situation
発展途中だし... だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
I'm still a work in progress... so I suddenly go out of pitch
その目に映らないだけだって やる気はメーター振り切って
Even if it doesn't show in your eyes, my motivation is off the charts
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
Always dreaming with all my might, and sleeping just as hard
ヤリちょい痩せた 調子づいて食った
I lost a little weight, so I got carried away and ate
それだけでなんで？敗北感
Just from that, why do I feel defeated?
すかさずに目標 下方修正して
Without delay, I revise my goals downward
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Being flexible and adaptable, the one who changes wins
柔軟に臨機応変　七変化が勝ち
Flexibility and adaptability, variety is the winner
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because actually I'm crazy
孔雀たちはそう　ここぞというとき美を魅せるんです
Peacocks show their beauty at the most crucial moments
五臓六腑　満身　邁進　願望は痩身　麗人
Whole body and soul, pushing forward, I long to be a slim beauty
誘惑多発だし…　だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Temptations are everywhere... so my will gets broken so easily
ヤバ　まさかの赤点！？　いや　ギリクリア！
Oh no, a failing grade?! No, barely passed!
それだけでなんて全能感
Just that gives me such a sense of omnipotence
大事なのは自分　認めてくこと
The important thing is to acknowledge yourself
自分を許さなきゃ　他人も許せない
If you don't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だってお本当はcrazy
Because actually I'm crazy
白鳥たちはそう　見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Swans flutter their feet where they can't be seen
本能に従順　忠実　翻弄も重々承知
Obedient and faithful to instinct, fully aware of being toyed with
前途洋々だし…　だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright... so I take a break sometimes
ふー…　はーあ…
Phew... Haa...
皆さん、水飲んでいいっすか？
Everyone, is it okay if I drink some water?
水飲んでいいっすか？
Can I drink some water?
んー…
Mm...
うまし、うまし。喉鳴った。
Delicious, delicious. My throat made a sound.
えっつ、とりあえず「Don't say lazy」どうでした？
Anyway, how was "Don't say lazy"?
もうなんかね、この曲はかっこいいから…
You know, this song is so cool...
もうなんか、かっこよく歌えてたかな？
So, I wonder if I was able to sing it coolly?
もうなんかさ、心臓が、心臓がドキドキしてるよ、僕も。
My heart is, my heart is pounding like crazy.
はーあ…
Haa...
でもね、まだまだ聴いてほしい歌がたくさんあるので、
But there are still many songs I want you all to hear,
それも楽しみにしてて下さい。
so please look forward to those as well.
お、ここで何やらゲストの、ゲストが来てくれるらしいー！
Oh, it seems like a guest, a guest is going to join us!
誰だ？
Who is it?
みんな誰だと思う？みんなゲスト誰だと思う？ちょっと予想、予想。
Who do you all think it is? Try to guess, guess.
ころさん。ころさんしかいないね。
Koro-san. It's gotta be Koro-san.
ころさんしかないじゃん。僕の大事な人ですよ。僕の大事な人がね、
It can only be Koro-san. She's my important person. My important person...
来てくれますよ。
is coming.
皆さん呼んでもいいですか？
Can I call her out, everyone?
よし、では僕の大事な人と言えば…言っていきましょうか。
Alright, so speaking of my important person... let's name them.
えー、シオン、
Um, Shion,
あくあ、
Aqua,
えー、スバルちゃん…
Uh, Subaru-chan...
おい！おい！
Hey! Hey!
どこ？
Where?
ここだよ。右下、右下だよ。
I'm right here. Bottom right, I'm at the bottom right.
ここか。ういしょ。きたー！ころさんだーい！
Over here? Whoops. There she is! It's Koro-san!
いろいろ言いたいことあるんですけど。シオン？スバルちゃん？あくあちゃん？
I have many things I want to say. Shion? Subaru-chan? Aqua-chan?
一番大事な人は最後に取っておくのが、そういう奴じゃん。
You save the most important person for last, that's just how it goes.
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
そうだよ。
That's right.
おかゆ。
Okayu.
おかゆ大好き。
I love Okayu.
ころさーん！
Koro-san!
待って。ちょっと音質がちょっとヤバいかもしれないけど、大丈夫かな？聞こえてる？
Wait. The sound quality might be a bit bad, but is it okay? Can you hear me?
でも大丈夫。なんか「カツオだよ」とか書かれてる。
It's fine. People are commenting stuff like "It's a bonito".
カツオじゃねぇ！
I'm not a bonito!
「カツオ来たよ」とか言われてる。
They're saying "The bonito is here".
おかゆ、おめでとう。
Okayu, congratulations.
ありがとう。今日何しに来てくれたの？
Thank you. What did you come for today?
今日は、せっかくのおかゆがこうやってアイドル衣装を着て配信してるから、
Today, since Okayu is streaming in her idol outfit like this,
ま、ちょっといろんなポーズをとってもらおうかなと思って。
well, I thought I'd have you do some various poses.
いろんなポーズ？
Various poses?
そう。
Yes.
何々、どんな、どんなポーズをさせようとしてるの、僕に。
What, what, what kind of poses are you trying to make me do?
え、今もうやっちゃっていいの？
Eh, is it okay to start now?
いいよ。
Okay.
いい？
Okay?
いいよ。
Okay.
じゃあ、マジで這いつくばってくれる？
Then, could you really crawl on all fours?
え、じゃあ...
Eh, then...
あ、じゃあ這いつくばります。這いつくばるって何、こういうこと？
Ah, then I'll crawl. What does crawling mean, like this?
あ、いいねいいね、そうそう、這いつくばって。
Ah, good, good, yes, yes, crawling.
カメラマンさんに指示がある。
I have instructions for the cameraman.
いい感じ、カメラ目線。
Looking good, camera eye contact.
あ、カメラ、カメラマンさん、ちょっともうちょっと上からかな？
Ah, camera, cameraman, maybe a little more from above?
ねぇ、背筋死ぬよ。
Hey, my back muscles are gonna die.
背筋死ぬよ。
My back muscles are gonna die.
あ、可愛い。ちょ、カメラ目線できる？
Ah, cute. Hey, can you look at the camera?
背筋、これ以上顔上げたら僕背筋死んじゃうけど。
Back muscles, if I lift my face any more than this, my back muscles will die.
じゃあ、じゃあカメラマンさんがちょっと下がってもらおう。
Then, then let's have the cameraman lower a bit.
そうだね。
That's right.
下に。いける？カメラマンさん。
Down. Can you do it, cameraman?
もっと下？
Lower?
下だよ、下、下。
Lower, lower, lower.
あ、いいんじゃないいいんじゃない？
Ah, isn't that good?
で、ちょっとね、うーん、左側にこう、体の、お尻もちょっと見えるぐらいに。
And, a little bit, hmm, to the left, like, so we can see the body's... buttocks a little too.
待ってよカメラマンさん。動けます？
Wait a second, cameraman. Can you move?
めっちゃ困っとるじゃんカメラマンさん。
The cameraman looks really troubled.
どう？もっと？僕の元？
How is it? More? To my place?
あ、怖い怖い怖い怖い。
Ah, scary, scary, scary, scary.
こう？
Like this?
あ、いい、尻尾揺らして尻尾揺らして。
Ah, good, wag your tail, wag your tail.
あ、いい感じいい感じ。
Ah, looking good, looking good.
あ、いいよいいよ、そう、そっちがいい、そっちがいい、そっちがいい。
Ah, good, good, yes, that's better, that's better, that's better.
あ、可愛い、可愛い、可愛い。
Ah, cute, cute, cute.
にゃーにゃー。
Nya nya.
そしたら、じゃあ、少し体を起こしてもらって。
Then, well, please raise your body a little.
ほい。
Okay.
起こせる？
Can you raise it?
起こした。
I raised it.
いいよ。あ、起こした。
Good. Ah, you raised it.
えーっと、顎に、え、両手でグーパンチ。
Um, to the chin, eh, fist punches with both hands.
うわ。
Uwa.
あ、そうそうそう。
Ah, yes, yes, yes.
そうそうそうそう。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
でちょっと、そう、それでちょっと、なんか照れてる感じをやってほしいな。
And a little bit, yes, like that, I want you to do a shy feeling.
照れてないもん。
I'm not shy.
照れてるでしょ。
You are shy, right.
照れてないもん。
I'm not shy.
あ、あ、可愛いね。
Ah, ah, cute.
やだ。
No.
あ、可愛いね。
Ah, cute.
やだー。やだー。
Nooo. Nooo.
あ、ごめんね。
Ah, sorry.
じゃあ、そしたら後ろ向いて。
Well, then, turn around.
ほう。
Ho.
ふ、振り返ってほしいな、うん。
I want you to look back, yes.
どうやって振り返るの？
How do I look back?
振り返る。
Look back.
ねぇ...
Hey...
ちょっともじもじしながら。もじもじしながら。
While fidgeting a bit. While fidgeting.
え、立ってたほうがいいんじゃない？でも、そしたら。
Eh, wouldn't it be better to stand? But then.
あ、そ、立って立って。
Ah, yes, stand up, stand up.
うん。
Yeah.
で尻尾も映してほしいな、カメラマンさん、尻尾も。
And I want the tail to be shown too, cameraman, the tail too.
尻尾も映してほしい。
I want the tail shown too.
映ってる？尻尾まげ。
Is it shown? Tail curve.
あ、映ってる映ってる映ってる。
Ah, it's shown, it's shown, it's shown.
そしたら、ちょっと... してほしいな。
Then, a little bit... I want you to do.
え、何？
Eh, what?
ちらって後ろを振り返ってみてほしいな。
I want you to take a peek and look back.
こっち向くの？
Look this way?
ちらり。
Peek.
あ、可愛いね！
Ah, cute!
上手にできてる？
Am I doing it well?
うん、とっても上手だよ。可愛いね。
Yes, very well done. Cute.
ころさん大好き。
I love Koro-san.
え、今一瞬、一瞬死んだんですけど。
Eh, just now, I died for a moment.
死んだの？
You died?
死んだ。
I died.
おかゆー、ちょっと何見せつけてるの、これは。
Okayu, what are you showing off just now?
でも、おにぎりゃーのみんなも大好き。
But, I love all the Onigiri-ya too.
そうだね、それはまあ、致し方なし。
Right, well, that can't be helped.
そうなの。
That's right.
それは致し方なしだね。
That can't be helped.
致し方なし。
Can't be helped.
え、あとどうしよう...
Eh, what else should we do...
もう限界化しすぎて音質やばいじゃん。
I'm fangirling too much and the audio quality is getting bad.
ガガガガガガ...
Gagagagagaga...
待って、待って、やばい、怖いやばいかも、これ。
Wait, wait, this is bad, scary, it might be bad.
なんかね、テンションが上がるとともにね、回線も不安定になってきてる。
Somehow, as the excitement rises, the connection is getting unstable too.
やばいやばいやばい。
Bad, bad, bad.
やばい。
Bad.
もっと一緒にいたいのに。
I want to stay together more.
ガガガガ... ずっと一緒に、待って、これからずっと一緒にいようと思ってるんだけどさ、無理なのかな。
Gagaga... together forever, wait, I was thinking of being together forever, is it impossible?
でもなんか回線がね、ダメって言ってるよ。
But somehow the connection is saying no.
ほらもう連れて行かれ始めてるもん。
Look, you're already starting to be taken away.
やだ。
No.
やだの？
You don't want to?
やだ。ちょっとこれ...
No. Hey, this...
やだ。機材トラブルやめてもー。
No. Equipment trouble, stop it.
ころさんの方まで。
Even on Koro-san's side.
じゃ、じゃあなんかすごいカカカカってなっちゃってるから、なんか、どうする？シンプルな指示もらおうか、じゃあ。
Well, then, since it's becoming all stuttery, what should we do? Let's get a simple instruction then.
シンプルの、シンプルな指示。会話しようとするとガバババってなるから、なんか、こうして、こうして、みたいあな。
Simple, simple instruction. When we try to converse it glitches out, so, like, do this, do this.
にゃーにゃー。にゃーにゃー。にゃーにゃー。にゃーにゃー。にゃーにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー。
Nya nya. Nya nya. Nya nya. Nya nya. Nya nya nya nya nya.
どう？
How is it?
あ、聞こえてる？これ、聞こえてないのかな。可愛いよ。
Ah, can you hear? Maybe you can't hear this. You're cute.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
どんどんね、世界のバランスが崩れ始めてる。
Gradually, the balance of the world is starting to crumble.
聞こえてるの？あ、聞こえてる聞こえてる。やばい、もう連れて行かれそう、やばい。
Can you hear me? Ah, you can hear, you can hear. Oh no, I feel like I'm about to be taken away, oh no.
じゃあね！
Bye!
またね！
See ya!
じゃあねー！
Bye-bye!
待って！待って待って待って！
Wait! Wait, wait, wait!
またね、またね、またね！
See ya, see ya, see ya!
待って、待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
あー、何？
Ah, what?
あ、いってしまった。
Oh, she's gone.
連れて行かれたという方が正しいんだろうか？
Or should I say she was taken away?
本人はね、すごく痛がってたんですけどね。
She seemed to be in a lot of pain, though.
あー連れて行かれちゃいましたね。
Ah, she was taken away.
え、じゃあコメントから何か一つくらいやって、次の歌に行こうかな？
Well, should I do one thing from the comments and then move on to the next song?
みんな、みんな、どう、どう、どう？
Everyone, everyone, what, what, what?
何してほしい？何してほしい？
What do you want me to do? What do you want me to do?
どう、どう、どういうのがいい？
What, what, what kind of thing would be good?
にゃーにゃーポーズもやったし、振り向きもやったし...
I've done the meow-meow pose, and the look-back...
どうかな？どうかな？
I wonder? I wonder?
ちゅー？「ちゅー」は無理だよ「ちゅー」は。
A kiss? A kiss is impossible, a kiss is.
あ、投げキッス的なってこと？
Oh, you mean like a blown kiss?
じゃあ、やるか。じゃあ、カメラマンさんのカメラに向かってね、
Well, let's do it then. I'll blow a kiss to the cameraman's camera,
投げキッスするので、受け取ってください。
so please receive it.
じゃあ...
Well...
いいですか？行きますよ。
Are you ready? Here I go.
おにぎりゃーのみんな、いつも応援ありがとう。
To all the Onigirya, thank you for always supporting me.
ちゅっ。
*Kiss*
はい、次行くぞ！次行くぞ！
All right, moving on! Moving on!
次行くぞ！次行くぞ！次行くぞ！
Moving on! Moving on! Moving on!
では、次の曲、こちら！
Now, for the next song, this one!
吉原ラメント 作詞・作曲：亜沙
Yoshiwara Lamento Lyrics/Composition: Asa
江戸の街は今日も深く 夜の帳カケテいく
In the city of Edo, the night deepens further still tonight
鏡向いて紅を引いて 応じるまま受け入れるまま
Facing the mirror, applying rouge, complying and accepting as I am
橙色輝いた花 憧れてた望んでいた
The flower that glowed orange, I once yearned for it, I once wished for it
いつの間にか藍色の花 ければ私安くないわ
Before I knew it, it became an indigo flower; but I don't come cheap
まことは ただ一人のどなたかの為だけに
In truth, I wanted to bloom just for that one person
咲いていたかったのだけれど
And only for them, but...
運命はわっちの自由を奪い
Fate stole away my freedom
そいで歯車を回していくのでありんす
And so it continues to turn the gears of my life
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を抱くのね
A romance full of lies, and yet you still hold me
悲しいくらいに感じた振りの吉原 今日は雨
Yoshiwara, where I feigned feeling it to a sad degree; today it rains
貴方様どうか私を 買っていただけないでしょうか？
Oh, dear sir, won't you please purchase me?
咲き出す傘の群れに 濡れる私は雨
Amidst the cluster of opening umbrellas, I'm soaked in the rain
行き交う群れ 賑わう声が ひしめき合いもつれ合い
Crowds passing by, bustling voices, jostling and tangling together
願うことは どうかいつか 鳥かごの外連れ出して
What I pray for is that someday, you'll take me out of this birdcage
まことは 行く宛などなくなってしまいんしたのだけれど
In truth, I no longer have anywhere to go, but...
こなたの籠の中から見える 景色だけは
The scenery seen from within this cage
わっちをいつなる時も 癒してくれるのでありんす
Heals me no matter what time it may be
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を買うのね
A romance full of lies, and yet you still buy me
私に咲いた花びら 濡れる心に降るは雨
Petals that bloomed on me, rain falls on my soaking heart
貴方様どうか 私と一夜限りの戯れを
Oh, dear sir, won't you please have a one-night dalliance with me?
望むシミの数が 鈍く心に刺さる
The number of stains I desired pierces my heart dully
憂いを帯びた花 望む 果てる
A flower tinged with sorrow, wishing, perishing
ようこそおいでくんなまし
Welcome, please come inside
恋人ごっこの夜に 吐息「あっ」と鳴かせて
In a night of playing lovers, let out a sighing gasp
悲しいくらいに感じた振りの吉原 今日は雨
Yoshiwara, where I feigned feeling it to a sad degree; today it rains
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を抱くのね
A romance full of lies, and yet you still hold me
悲しいくらいに感じた振りの吉原 今日は雨
Yoshiwara, where I feigned feeling it to a sad degree; today it rains
貴方様どうか私を 買っていただけないでしょうか？
Oh, dear sir, won't you please purchase me?
咲き出す傘の群れに 濡れる私は雨
Amidst the cluster of opening umbrellas, I'm soaked in the rain
咲き出す傘の群れに　濡れる私は雨
In the cluster of opening umbrellas, I, drenched, am the rain.
はい。よしわらラメントだったんだけど、どうだったかな？
Okay. That was Yoshiwara Lament, how was it?
この歌はよく、あの、歌枠とかでやってる時に歌ったら、みんなすごいこの歌好きって言ってくれてたし...
Whenever I sang this song during my singing streams, everyone said they really loved it...
何より、僕のね、ばあちゃんがこの歌をめちゃめちゃ気に入ってて。
And more than anything, my grandmother really likes this song.
「おかゆのよしわらラメント好きなんだよね」って言ってたから...
"I love Okayu's Yoshiwara Lament," she said...
今日は僕の誕生日ということで、いつもお世話になってる、
Since today is my birthday, as a way to thank her who always looks after me...
まぁ今はね、そばには、同じお家には住んでないんですけど...
well, we don't live together in the same house now, but...
ばあちゃんがそう言ってくれたので、今回はこの歌を選ばせていただきました。
since Grandma said that, I chose this song for today.
どうだったみんな？セクシーじゃなかった僕？
How was it, everyone? Wasn't I sexy?
みんなにさ、投げキッスした後にさ、歌歌うとちょっとさ、
Singing right after giving you all a blowing kiss... it feels a bit like,
さっきの投げキッスすらも偽りだったんじゃないかみたいな感じになっちゃうんですけど。
even that kiss might have been a lie.
ばあちゃん見てる？ばあちゃん見てる？ばあちゃん！
Grandma, are you watching? Grandma, are you watching? Grandma!
ばあちゃん見てる？僕アイドルになっちゃったよ。
Grandma, are you watching? I've become an idol.
ばあちゃんにはね、ホロライブに入る時に、なんかゲーマーズっていうのがあって、そこで僕入れるらしいから行ってくるねって言ったんですけど。
When I joined Hololive, I told my grandma, "There's this thing called Gamers, and it seems like I can join, so I'm going."
ばあちゃんもまさか僕がね、この僕がアイドルになるだなんて思ってなかっただろうね、正直。
I'm sure even Grandma never imagined that I... of all people... would become an idol.
みんなコメントありがとうね。歌ってる時もね、みんなのコメント見ながらニマニマしてました。
Thanks for all the comments. Even while singing, I was grinning as I read them.
え、トレンド1位？本当に！？
Eh, trending #1? Really?!
ありがとう！これ、みんながおかゆの... #おかゆの生誕祭2021 をね、呟いてくれてるおかげだね。
Thank you! It's all thanks to everyone tweeting with #OkayuBirthday2021.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
じゃあ、次もね、あの、頑張って歌っていこうと思います。
Well then, I'll do my best to sing the next song too.
では、次の曲、どうぞ！
Now, here is the next song!
でも　そんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough
もう　そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's not enough anymore
心は進化するよ　もっともっと
The heart will evolve more and more
恋愛サーキュレーション
作詞:meg rock / 作曲:神前暁
Renai Circulation
Lyrics: meg rock / Composition: Satoru Kosaki
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If it's a relationship that vanishes when put into words
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
I thought I should just erase the words
恐れてた
I was afraid
だけど　あれ？なんか違うかも...
But wait? Maybe something's different...
せんりのみちもいっぽから！
Even a journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step!
石のようにかたい　そんな意志で
With a will as hard as a rock
ちりもつもればやまとなでしこ？
Dust becomes a mountain, Yamato Nadeshiko?
「し」ぬきで　いや死ぬ気で！
Without the "shi", no, with all my might!
ふわふわり　ふわふわる
Soft and fluffy, soft and fluffy
あなたが名前を呼ぶ　それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Just you calling my name makes me float in the air
ふわふわる　ふわふわり
Soft and fluffy, soft and fluffy
あなたが笑っている　それだけで笑顔になる
Just you laughing makes me smile
神様ありがとう　運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが　しあわせなの
The fact that we met is happiness
でも　そんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough
もう　そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's not enough anymore
心は進化するよ　もっともっと
The heart will evolve more and more
そう　そんなんじゃやだ
Yes, I don't want it to be like that
ねえ　そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough yet
私のこと見ててね　ずっとずっと
Keep watching me, forever and ever
私の中のあなたほど　あなたの中の私の存在は
As much as you are within me, my presence within you...
まだまだ大きくないことも　わかっているけれど
I know it's not that big yet, but...
今この同じ瞬間　共有してる実感
Feeling the reality of sharing this same moment now
ちりもつもればやまとなでしこ！
Dust becomes a mountain, Yamato Nadeshiko!
略して？　ちりつもやまとなでこ！
Shortened? Chiritsumo Yamato Nadeko!
くらくらり　くらくらる
Dizzy, dizzy
あなたを見上げたら　それだけでまぶしすぎて
Just looking up at you is too dazzling
くらくらる　くらくらり
Dizzy, dizzy
あなたを想っている　それだけでとけてしまう
Just thinking of you makes me melt
神様ありがとう　運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
It's a blessing that we could meet
コイスル キセツハ ヨクバリ circulation
In love, the season is a greedy circulation
コイスル キモチハ ヨクバリ circulation
In love, the feeling is a greedy circulation
コイスル ヒトミハ ヨクバリ circulation
In love, the eyes are a greedy circulation
コイスル オトメハ ヨクバリ circulation
In love, the maiden is a greedy circulation
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy-fluff, fluffy-fluff
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで 宙へ浮かぶ
Just you calling my name makes me float in the air
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluffy-fluff, fluffy-fluff
あなたが笑っている それだけで 笑顔になる
Just you laughing makes me smile too
神様 ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
It's a blessing that we could meet
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's not enough
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
No, that's not enough, look
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
My heart will evolve more and more
そう そんなんじゃ やだ
Yeah, that's not enough, I don't want that
ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Hey, that's not enough yet
私のこと見ててね ずっと ずっと
Keep looking at me, forever and ever
はぁー... はぁー... 照れ照れ
Haa... haa... so embarrassing.
いやー、この歌はさ、もうすっごい可愛いから、あの、僕、声カッコいいじゃん？
Wow, this song is really cute, right? And, well, I have a cool voice, don't I?
最近の口癖なんだけど。このカッコいい僕が、これを歌ってもいいのかなって思ってたんですけど、歌っちゃいましたね。
It's my recent catchphrase. I was wondering if it was okay for someone as cool as me to sing this, but I went ahead and did it.
歌っちゃいました。
I sang it.
あ、でもね、みんなが可愛いって言ってくれてるなら、いいのかなー... いいのかなー... いっか！
But well, if everyone is saying it's cute, then I guess it's okay... it's okay... whatever!
ありがとうみんな。見えてるよ、コメント。
Thank you, everyone. I can see your comments.
見えてるよー。アリーナ、えーっと、右！左！上！
I see you! Arena... um, right! Left! Up!
応援団みたいになっちゃったけど。右、左、上、下！
I sound like a cheering squad. Right, left, up, down!
聞こえるかーい？
Can you hear me?
聞こえてる。ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとうだよー。
You can hear me. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
はぁ。ちょっと深呼吸しようか。
Haa. Let's take a deep breath.
はぁー...
Haa...
よし、息も整ったことだし、次の歌に行こうと思うんですけど...
Alright, now that I've caught my breath, I'm thinking of moving on to the next song...
次の歌は、いつもね、僕が萌えているあの曲を、今日は燃えないけれど、歌っていこうかなと思います。
The next song is that one I'm always "moe-ing" over. I won't be burning up today, but I'm going to sing it.
音楽、準備はいい？
Are you ready for the music?
では、聴いてください。『炎（ほむら）』。
Please listen. "Homura".
さよなら ありがとう 声の限り
Goodbye, thank you, with all my voice
悲しみよりもっと大事なこと
Something more important than sadness
去りゆく背中に伝えたくて ぬくもりと痛みに間に合うように
I wanted to tell your retreating back, to make it in time with the warmth and the pain
このまま続くと思っていた 僕らの明日を描いていた
I thought it would continue like this, I was drawing our tomorrow
呼び合っていた光がまだ 胸の奥に熱いのに
The light that called out to each other is still hot deep in my chest
僕たちは燃え盛る旅の途中で出会い
We met in the middle of a blazing journey
We met in the midst of a blazing journey
手を取りそして離した 未来のために
We took each other's hands and then let go, for the sake of the future
夢が一つ叶うたび 僕は君を想うだろう
Every time a dream comes true, I will probably think of you
強くなりたいと願い 泣いた 決意を餞に
Wishing to become stronger, I cried; with determination as a parting gift
懐かしい思いに囚われたり 残酷な世界に泣き叫んで
Being trapped in nostalgic memories, crying out to the cruel world
大人になるほど増えて行く もう何一つだって失いたくない
Increasing as we grow up, I don't want to lose even one more thing
悲しみに飲まれ落ちてしまえば 痛みを感なくなれるけれど
If I'm swallowed by sadness and fall, I'll stop feeling the pain, but...
君の言葉 君の願い 僕は守りぬくと誓ったんだ
Your words, your wish; I swore to protect them to the end
音を立てて崩れ落ちて行く
It's crumbling down with a sound
一つだけの かけがえのない世界
The one and only, irreplaceable world
手を伸ばし抱き止めた 激しい光の束
Reaching out and catching a fierce bundle of light
輝いて消えてった 未来のために
It shone and then disappeared, for the sake of the future
託された幸せと 約束を超えて行く
Going beyond the happiness and promises entrusted to me
振り返らずに進むから 前だけ向いて叫ぶから
Because I'll move forward without looking back, because I'll look only ahead and shout
心に炎を灯して 遠い未来まで……
Lighting a fire in my heart, until the far-off future...
はい！ということでついにこんなね、
Yes! So, the dream of singing 'Homura'
大舞台で炎を歌う夢が叶いました。ありがとうございます。
on such a big stage has finally come true. Thank you very much.
いや、炎はいいよね。僕の胸もいつも燃えていますよ。
Man, 'Homura' is great, isn't it? My heart is always burning too.
はい。
Yes.
あ、でもね、ちょっと察しのいいみんなはさ、
Ah, but you know, for those of you who are quick on the uptake,
いつも僕が配信で終わる時に炎を歌ってるから、
since I always sing 'Homura' when I finish a stream,
あ、これで終わりなんだなって思いました？
did you think 'Ah, this is the end'?
思いました？
Did you?
実は、ちっちっち。今日は一味違うんだな〜。
Actually, tsk tsk tsk. Today is a little different!
ということで、炎の次に、もう一個あるんですけど、
So, after 'Homura', there's one more thing,
その前にその前にその前に！
but before that, before that, before that!
めちゃめちゃね、素晴らしいお知らせがございます。
I have some very wonderful news.
準備はいいですか？
Are you ready?
はい！では、いきますよ！
Yes! Then, here we go!
グッズの告知です！ドーン！
It's an announcement for goods! Boom!
猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2021、2月22日本日発売です！
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Commemoration Goods 2021 are on sale today, February 22nd!
イエーイ、イエーイ、イエーイ！
Yay, yay, yay!
あ、僕がよく配信で流してる曲だ。よくご存知で。
Ah, it's the song I often play in my streams. You know it well.
えー、ということでですね、グッズの説明をしていきたいと思います。
Well then, I'd like to explain the goods.
まずこちらのね、あのメインのイラストになっている神岡ちろる先生描き下ろし
First, this main illustration drawn by Kamioka Chirol-sensei,
「お家にお邪魔しまーす」等身大タペストリー...
'Coming over to your house' life-size tapestry...
猫又おかゆ 誕生日記念2021 2月22日 販売開始
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Commemoration 2021 - Sales start Feb 22nd
…等身大タペストリーと、トゥーミ先生描き下ろし、おかゆも日が経てば増えるさマグカップ。
...a life-sized tapestry, and the "Okayu multiplies as the days go by" mug by Toomi-sensei.
そしてこちら2点、全グッズセットを購入してくださった方には、特典として、猫又おかゆからの複製手書きラブレターが届きまーす！
And if you buy the full set, you'll receive a replica handwritten love letter from me as a bonus!
なんとラブレターも届いちゃうんだよね。
You even get a love letter!
で、えーじゃあまず1つ1つ説明していきたいと思います。あ、こっちですね。
So, let's go through them one by one. Ah, this way.
まず1つ目は、千露露先生が描き下ろしてくださった、僕の等身大タペストリーです。
First is my life-sized tapestry drawn by Chirol-sensei.
僕はアホ毛込みで152cmなんだけど、お家に飾ったら僕がお家にいるかのようなサイズ感でお邪魔します。
I'm 152cm including my cowlick, but it'll feel like I'm actually in your home when you hang it up.
神岡ちろる先生というのは僕のママです。僕のイラストを担当してくださっているママが今回描き下ろしてくれました！
Chirol Kamioka-sensei is my "mama." My illustrator mama drew this for me!
めっちゃデカい、見て！180cmあるのよ、高く。
It's huge, look! It's 180cm tall.
あ、アホ毛抜きだったっけか。ちょっと後で測りましょう、身長。
Ah, was that height without the cowlick? Let's check that later.
70cm×160cmだって。こー、こんなんだよマジで。
It says it's 70cm x 160cm. It's like... this big, seriously.
ぜひね、ぜひ僕を、僕をお家に入れてください！
Please, please let me into your home!
ちょっと伝え方によっては不審なんですけど、あの、僕をお家に入れてください。はい、では次です。
That sounds a bit suspicious depending on how you take it, but... please let me into your home. Okay, next.
次の説明に行きたいと思います。こちら！えー、トゥーミ先生描き下ろし、おかゆも日が経てば増えるさマグカップ！
Moving on to the next one. This! The "Okayu multiplies as the days go by" mug drawn by Toomi-sensei!
こちらはですね、あのトゥーミ先生という方がですね、マグカップのイラストを書いてくださいました。
For this one, Toomi-sensei drew the illustration for the mug.
で、このマグカップの手の部分、持ち手の部分が猫のね、この僕の、僕のね、このしっぽみたいになってんで、ほらほら！
And the handle of this mug is like a cat's... my tail! Look, look!
すごいでしょ、ほらほら！こんな感じでね、このようなしっぽの取っ手となっております。
Amazing, right? Look! It has a tail handle like this.
でもあんまり強く掴みすぎるなよ！
But don't grab it too hard!
これね、僕ゲーマーズなんで、こうゲームセンター仕様のデザインになってます。
Since I'm in Gamers, it has a game center-themed design.
めちゃめちゃ可愛いよね！僕も、僕も欲しい！僕の家にも配送してください。はい。
It's super cute! I want one too! Please ship one to my house as well.
えーっと、20、あれ、何時からブース公開ですか？スタッフー！
Um... what time does the BOOTH store open? Staff!
はい、えー概要欄にね、あのブースのURLがあるので、もう飛んだら買えるのかな？どうですかね？
The BOOTH URL is in the description. Can you buy it if you go there now? I wonder.
10時25分ですか？
10:25 PM?
はい、今連絡があったんですけど、販売は10時25分から、えーブースで買えるようになるみたいなので、皆さんよかったらね、あの買ってみてください。
I just got word. Sales start at 10:25 PM on BOOTH, so please check it out if you'd like.
よろしくお願いします。めちゃめちゃ可愛いと思います。えーっと、えーじゃあやりますか。ぎこちないな。
Thank you. I think it's really cute. Well... shall we do it? This is awkward.
じゃあ、皆さん、これで終わりではございません。
Now, everyone, this isn't the end.
僕は、僕はこの数ヶ月間も言いたくて言いたくて言いたくて仕方なかったことがね、あるんですよ実はね、実実実は。
Actually, there's something I've been wanting and wanting to say for months now.
最近ホロライブのみんな、オリジナルの曲出してるよねー。
Lately, everyone in Hololive has been releasing original songs.
あれいいなーって思ってさ、僕もいいなーって。
I thought, "That's so nice," and wanted one too.
作っちゃいました！イエーイ！わーいわーいわーい！
So I made one! Yay! Whoo!
ということで、えー本日はですね、その歌を歌っちゃいたいと思います！
So today, I'm going to sing that song!
あの僕のチャンネルにハテナハテナハテナっていう動画が今上がってるんですけど、そちらの方でPVだったりとかが、こうしっかり見れるバージョンの動画があるので、
There's a video titled "???" on my channel right now where you can watch the full MV version.
22時半にプレミア公開されるのでよかったら一緒に見ましょう皆さん。
It'll premiere at 10:30 PM, so let's watch it together, everyone.
ということで、歌っていきたいと思います。よし、じゃあ一回深呼吸してから歌うね。
And now, I'm going to sing it. Okay, I'll take a deep breath first.
では、僕の初めてのオリジナル曲。
Now, my very first original song.
あ、その前に水飲んでいい？
Ah, can I drink some water first?
はい。では行きたいと思います。
Okay. Here we go.
聴いてください。もぐもぐYUMMY！
Please listen. Mogu Mogu YUMMY!
もぐもぐYUMMY！
Mogu Mogu YUMMY!
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Lyrics/Music: PinocchioP
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も
Even the struggles of all creation...
マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる？
...will mostly become delicious if you put mayonnaise on them?
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, I'll get hungry.
消化できなかった「ごめんごめん。」
I couldn't digest that "I'm sorry, I'm sorry."
酸いも甘いも 勝手に食べて
Eating both the sour and the sweet as I please,
ご迷惑おかけしています
I apologize for the trouble.
パクチーな掟 変な味のジュース
Coriander rules, weird-tasting juice.
心を無にして飲みこみます
I'll empty my mind and swallow it down.
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで
Ah, chaos. In a restaurant of information overload,
嘘っぱちのメニューにお茶をこぼして
Spilling tea on a fake menu.
なんじゃこりゃー！
What is this?!
おい、出してくれ！
Hey, let me out!
今日はなんて日だ！
What a day this is!
オリ曲を初めて歌ってるときに
Right when I'm singing my original song for the first time,
蓋をされたぞ！
The lid's been closed on me!
今年は やばいんじゃないのちょっと
This year is looking pretty bad, isn't it?
もう一回歌わせてくれよ！
Let me sing it one more time!
もう一回... おい、ちょっとみんな聞いたか今？
One more time... Hey, did everyone hear that just now?
今 みんなには聞こえない声で「トークで繋いでください」とかいう無茶振りされたぞ、みんな！
Just now, a voice you couldn't hear gave me a reckless order to "fill the time with talk," everyone!
僕じゃなきゃこれ 怒ってますよ！
If it weren't me, I'd be angry!
うええ... 「トークで繋いでください」って言われた。
Waaah... They told me to fill the time with talk.
僕 フリートーク苦手でさ、いつも雑談する前に事前にみんなから雑談の話題募ってるぐらいなのにね。
I'm bad at free talk, you know? I usually even gather talk topics from everyone beforehand.
なんて日だよ本当に、本当に本当に。ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと。
What a day, seriously. Really, really. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
うええ... なんて日だよ、僕が何したって言うんだよ。
Waaah... What a day. What did I ever do?
うう... ね、もう一回聞けるからっていう意味では確かにいいかもしれないね。
Ugh... Well, in the sense that we can hear it one more time, maybe it's actually a good thing.
確かに、ねえ。
For sure, right?
ね、今日やばいよね。画質も最初やばかったし。
Right, today is crazy. The resolution was terrible at the start too.
あの、ころさんの回線も謎にやばかったし。
And, like, Korone-san's connection was inexplicably bad too.
まさかの最後の最後でこんなことになってしまうっていうね。
And then this happens at the very end.
うええ... これじゃ僕が先に歌う前にプレミア公開されちゃうよ。
Waaah... At this rate, the premiere will start before I can sing it.
僕が先かプレミア公開が先かみたいなとこちょっとあるよね。
It's like a race between me and the premiere.
うええ... やばい、自分の動画に負けるの僕。
Waaah... This is bad, I'm going to lose to my own video.
ちなみにね、22時半からあの、公開されるのでね
By the way, it'll be released at 22:30,
そちらも、そちらも見ていただければなと思います。はい。
so I'd love for you to watch that as well. Yes.
でもやばい、僕より先にそっちがね、公開されてしまう可能性がちょっと出てきていますね。
But this is bad, there's a possibility that it will be released before I finish.
どっちが先か、プレミア公開が先か、おかゆが先か。
Which will be first? The premiere or Okayu?
負けたくないよ、負けたくないよ。
I don't want to lose, I don't want to lose.
やばい、あと15分、あと15分。助けて、助けてよ。
Oh no, 15 minutes left, 15 minutes. Help me, help me.
でもね、ここで誰も助けられないのが現実なんだよな。おかゆ。
But the reality is that no one can help me here. Okayu.
うええ...
Waaah...
いや、これ負けるかもしれないな。負けるかもしれないんだけど。
Man, I might lose. I might lose, but...
たくさんの人が見てくれてるみたいです。みんなありがとう。
Seems like a lot of people are watching. Thanks, everyone.
でも今、僕はあの壁の中に閉じ込められてます。
But right now, I'm trapped inside that wall.
壁の中に閉じ込められてるよ。出してよ。
I'm trapped inside the wall. Let me out.
お腹も空いてきたし、どうしよう。
I'm getting hungry too, what should I do?
うええ... あ、今誰か、なんかスパナがついたホロライブのメンバーがすーって通っていった。
Waaah... Ah, a Hololive member with a wrench just zipped by.
誰だった？誰だった今の。
Who was it? Who was that just now?
みんな、誰だった今の？誰だった今の？
Everyone, who was that? Who was that just now?
みおちゃん？みおしゃ？
Mio-chan? Miosha?
みおしゃー！
Miosha—!
みおちゃんはいないんだ今日は。みおしゃー！
Mio-chan isn't here today. Miosha—!
うええ... こんなお預けってないよね。みんなも辛いよね。
Waaah... This is such a tease. It's tough for you guys too, right?
みんなも辛いよね、「えっ」って。マジ？ここで？
You guys must be suffering too, like "What?". Seriously? Right here?
ね、そんな感じですよね。僕も歌いたいなあ。
Yeah, it's like that. I want to sing too.
あー。
Aah.
お、おかゆ先輩！聞こえる？
O-Okayu-senpai! Can you hear me?
聞こえる！
I can!
おかゆ先輩、天音かなたです。来たよ！
Okayu-senpai, it's Amane Kanata. I'm here!
かなたん！
Kanatan!
かなたん、助っ手...
Kanatan, help...
おかゆ先輩！おかゆ先輩！
Okayu-senpai! Okayu-senpai!
かなたん、僕今、壁に閉じ込められてる。
Kanatan, I'm trapped in the wall right now.
ああー！
Aaaah!
おかゆ先輩が見えねえよ！
I can't see you, Okayu-senpai!
この... この封鎖されてる壁がよぉ！ちょっと！
This... This wall that's blocking me! Come on!
笑った。この前さ、この前一緒に見たさ...
That's funny. Remember what we saw together the other day...
あの、進撃の巨人でもこういう展開あったよね。
...that scene in Attack on Titan? It was just like this.
壁の中にずっと閉じ込め... 巨人じゃないですよおかゆ先輩は！
Being trapped inside the walls... You're not a Titan, Okayu-senpai!
ずっと見てますよ、おかゆ先輩。
I've been watching you the whole time, Okayu-senpai.
オリジナル曲もう一曲いこうかな。
I think I'll sing another original song.
ぜひ歌ってください。
Please do sing it.
ねー、歌いたいよ。
Yeah, I want to sing.
歌いましょうねー。
Let's sing then.
ねーーー。
Yeahhhh.
なんかかなたん今日声可愛くない？めっちゃ。
Doesn't Kanatan's voice sound super cute today?
え、いや僕思ってたんだけど、おかゆ先輩も今日めっちゃ声可愛くないっすか？
Eh, actually I was thinking the same thing about you, Okayu-senpai!
えー？
Really?
いや多分みんな思ってたと思うわ。今日なんか初手からさ、あれ？おかゆ先輩なんかいつも可愛いけど、え？今日もっと可愛い！みたいな。
I'm sure everyone thinks so. Right from the start, I was like, Okayu-senpai is always cute, but today she's even cuter!
もうね、あれなのかもしれない。焦りすぎて声がちょっと上ずっちゃってるのかもしれない。
Maybe it's because I'm so flustered that my voice is a bit higher than usual.
可愛いです、本当に。おかゆ先輩、もう本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます。
It's really cute. Anyway, Happy Birthday, Okayu-senpai!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
まだかな、まだかな、この壁は... まだかな、まだかな... ちょっといっぱいホロメン呼んで来ちゃうかな、僕。
Is it time yet? This wall... Maybe I should go call a bunch of other Hololive members.
でもかなたん、なんか今ね、朗報が入った。
But Kanatan, I just got some good news.
お、何？何？何？
Oh, what is it? What?
僕はついに壁から出られるらしい。
It seems I can finally leave the wall.
おー！本当ですか！？それでは脱出します！
Oh! Really!? Then I'll make my escape!
ちょっと観客席に紛れ込むから！またね！
I'm going to blend into the audience! See ya!
ありがとうかなたん！バイバイ！
Thank you, Kanatan! Bye-bye!
はぁ〜、天使だなマジでかなたん。
Sigh... Kanatan really is an angel.
かなたんのおかげで、どうにかいけそうらしいです。はぁ〜、よかった〜。
Thanks to Kanatan, it looks like I'll manage somehow. Phew, what a relief.
あ〜みんな！ギリギリ勝った！自分の動画にギリギリ勝てました！セーフ！
Ah, everyone! I barely won! I barely beat my own video! Safe!
マジホロメンあったけぇ。ということで、今日改めて行きたいと思います。
The Hololive members are so warm-hearted. So, let's get back to it.
もう一回いきますよ！もぐもぐ〜YUMMY！
Let's do this once more! Mogu Mogu Yummy!
もぐもぐYUMMY! 作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Mogu Mogu Yummy! Lyrics/Composition: PinocchioP
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる？
Even the hard struggles of all creation... Do they mostly become delicious if you add mayonnaise?
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ 消化できなかった「ごめんごめん」
Even if you cry, I'll get hungry. The 'sorry, sorry' that I couldn't digest.
酸いも甘いも勝手に食べて ご迷惑おかけしています
Eating sour and sweet things as I please. I'm sorry for causing trouble.
パクチーな掟 変な味のジュース 心を無にして飲み込みます
Cilantro rules, strange tasting juice. I'll swallow it while emptying my heart.
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで 嘘っぱちのメニューにお茶こぼして
Ah, in a chaotic restaurant with too much information, spilling tea on a fake menu.
君ともぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munching with you, munch munch.
銃撃戦の真ん中でもぐもぐ（うぎゃ〜）
Munching in the middle of a gunfight (ugya~).
魑魅魍魎 ハラペコの群れ 満腹になる未来を願っているよ
A hungry swarm of monsters. I'm wishing for a future where everyone is full.
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munch munch, munch munch.
世界が終わる前に
Before the world ends.
もぐもぐやみぃ マジ神 やむやむありのまんま
Munch munch yummy, seriously god-tier. Yum yum, just as it is.
もぐもぐやみぃ Magic Coming この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Munch munch yummy, Magic Coming. Taste this world, delicious.
リバーブかかってなくないか？
Wait, isn't there any reverb?
おや？
Oh?
理論武装のミルフィーユサンド（サンド）
Mille-feuille sandwich of theoretical armament (sand).
匿名希望のオーロラソース（ソース）
Aurora sauce of anonymous request (sauce).
大雑把な味付け 多めに見てよ 美味しくなったら「おk おk」
Forgive the rough seasoning. If it becomes delicious, it's ok ok.
良いモン悪いモン いっぱい食べて 汚れた口元拭います
Eat lots of good things and bad things. I'll wipe my dirty mouth.
おにぎり ピザ ケーキ 豪華なフルコース 罠を疑い気をつけます
Onigiri, pizza, cake, a luxurious full course. I'll suspect traps and be careful.
ああ 妄想流言蜚語のバイキングで 毒入りと絶品料理 選り分けて
Ah, at a buffet of delusions and false rumors, sorting poisoned and superb dishes.
君ともぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munching with you, munch munch.
デスゲームの教室でもぐもぐ（うぎゃ〜）
Munching in a death game classroom (ugya~).
魑魅魍魎 ハラペコの群れ 仲の良い君と生き残れたらいいな
A hungry swarm of monsters. It'd be nice to survive with you, my good friend.
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munch munch, munch munch.
数年後もこの場所で
In this place even years later.
もぐもぐやみぃ マジ神 今夜の晩ごはんは
Munch munch yummy, seriously god-tier. Tonight's dinner is...
もぐもぐやみぃ Magic Coming 次はお前の番だ
Munch munch yummy, Magic Coming. Next is your turn.
もぐもぐやみぃ
Munching yummy
マジ神 やむやむありのまんま
Pure bliss, yum yum, just as I am
もぐもぐやみぃ Magic Coming
Munching yummy, Magic Coming
この世を味わうんだ
Savoring this world
うまうま うまうま
Tasty, tasty
もぐもぐもぐもぐ もぐもぐもぐもぐ もぐもぐやみぃ
Munch, munch, munch, munch... munching yummy
もぐもぐもぐもぐ もぐもぐもぐもぐ もぐもぐやみぃ やみぃ
Munch, munch, munch... munching yummy, yummy
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
22時半にまたお会いしましょう！
Let's meet again at 22:30!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
お誕生日 3D配信
猫又おかゆ
Birthday 3D Stream
Nekomata Okayu